# 上面喽
Noodles are ready!
# 油泼面走起
Come and have Biang Biang noodles
# 捞起捞起 挑福挑寿
may the long noodles bring blessing and longevity (blessing words)
# 主料是面粉 碱 这是和面的
The main ingredients are flour and dietary alkali
# 小料呢 陕西的辣椒粉
Other ingredients include chili pepper powder from Shanxi
# 小葱花 蒜蓉 芝麻 大葱就这些
chopped green onion, minced garlic, sesame, and spring onion, that's all
# 第一步叫小国先把面和上
First let Xiaoguo start the dough
# 行嘞
Got it
# 碱 盐是筋碱是骨
dietary alkali together with salt are the muscles and bones of the dough
# （有碱）面吃的筋道
noddles are al dente this way
# 一斤面搁多少碱 两克碱
in 1 jin (500 g) flour, 2 grams of alkali is good
# 还要搁点盐
plus some salt
# 你这温水凉水啊小国
Xiaoguo, is this warm or cold water?
# 温水就行
Warm water is good
# 魏刚强你要做什么啊
Wei Gangqiang, what are you doing?
# 他做这浇头
He's making the topping
# 这个面和的像面条面似的
This dough turns out like normal noodle doughs
# 就硬一点
But a little harder
# 基本一斤面四两半水就行
Generally 1 jin (500 g) flour goes with 4.5 liang (225 g) water
# 网友们记住了啊
Viewer friends, remember:
# 你要放五两水它就软了
If you put 5 liang (250 g) water the dough would be too soft
# 不好了 就成了饺子面了
That would be a dumpling dough, but not good for this
# 刚强同志把最累的活交给元国了
Gangqiang Tongzhi just gave the hardest labor to Yuango
# 饧五分钟咱再揉一遍
Let the dough rest for 5 minutes and let's knead more
# 待会再出条
We'll cut strips later
# 你先饧着我这耗着葱油
Can you watch the dough, I will make some scallion oil
# 葱油离不开菜籽油
Scallion oil can't go without canola oil
# 用葱炼一下 菜籽油香啊
Infuse with scallion. Canola oil smells nice!
# 在西北西南 他们都用菜籽油
In the Southwest and Northwest, people all use canola oil
# 传统的油泼面不加金黄的葱
Traditional Biang Biang noddles do not have fried scallions in them
# 咱今天留着 改变一下口味
Let's keep the scallions today to spice it up
# 一块给它拌进去
Mix it in altogether
# 元国 面怎么样了
Yuanguo, how is the dough?
# 饧十分钟了 师父和大爷
Master and Da Ye, it's been resting for 10 minutes
# 咱们先下胚子 搓成条
Let's first split the dough into strips
# 饧好了之后稍微来抹一点油
After the dough is done resting, let's put some oil on the surface
# 不让它干了
So that it doesn't dry
# 小剂子
Make small splits of the dough
# 这胚子做完了还要饧
After we split it, it needs to rest more
# 好比说今天你和完了面
It's like if you mix the dough today
# 放冰箱里 时间越长越好
You put it in the fridge, the longer the better
# 第二天使 更好使一些
It will be even better the next day
# 这样 一擀
Roll the rolling pin over like this
# 擀成这样
Into this shape
# 擀成这种条 待会好抻
Into strips, so we can stretch it later
# 中间一压
Press it in the middle
# 这一片刷一次油 这离不开油
Brush oil on each piece, it can't live without the oil
# 刷好了往冰箱里一放
Once it's ready, put it in the fridge
# 其实做面食这饧面很重要
In fact, resting the dough is crucial to make dough food
# 面饧的好
If it rests well
# 做出来的效果就是好
The food will be turn out well
# 行了 封保鲜膜 搁一边
Ok, let's seal it with plastic film and set it aside
# 网友们 时间的问题
Viewer friends, due to limited time
# 我们有提前和好的
We have ready dough here
# 因为它有一个饧的过程
Because it has to go through the process of resting
# 这个饧了仨小时 最好是一夜
This one rested for 3 hours, but overnight would be better
# 对比一下
Here, compare it
# 小魏再接着拿走饧去
Xiaowei, take this and let it rest more
# 慢慢的啊
Be careful
# 油泼辣子biangbiang面 一撕
Chili oil and Biang Biang noodles; tear it
# 好 一根
Ok, one is done
# 从中间往外 慢慢的
from the middle out, slowly
# 一拉 一摔
stretch it, and hit it once on the counter
# biangbiangbiang有声音
it has the "Biang Biang" sound
# 过年喽 吃点好面
It's the Lunar New Year, let's celebrate with good noodles
# 这面吃着又筋道又好吃
This noodle is al dente and delicious
# 瞧这面煮的啊 跟裤腰带似的
Look at the noodles, they cook like wolven cloth belts
# 这个面很快 陕西几大怪
These noodles don't cook for a long time. One specialty of Shanxi:
# 面条像腰带
Noodles like woven belts
# 来了
Here it comes
# 关键时刻
The critical moment
# 来一勺盐
Add a spoonful of salt
# 酱油
soy sauce
# 醋
vinegar
# 根据自己的口味
To your taste
# 陕西人爱吃醋
Shanxi people love vinegar
# 刚才炸的这个（葱）
This scallion we just fried
# 他们原来没有这个
They traditionally don't use this
# 炸葱油的葱留着
But we keep the scallion from the scallion oil
# 干焙一下在锅里头 辣椒面
Heat it up in the wok, and chili powder
# 焙一下更香一些
It gets more aromatic if you heat it up
# 葱花
Scallion
# 蒜蓉 这是灵魂
And minced garlic is the soul
# （熟）芝麻
Baked sesame
# 稍微点点儿胡椒粉
And a tiny bit of pepper
# 少来点香油
Add a little more sesame oil
# 那一呲 哗啦哗啦的
That pour will give the sizzling sound
# 好 浇油喽
Alright, let's pour
# 油温八成热
The oil temperature is about 240 ℃
# 油泼面 要呲呲熟了
Biang Biang noodles are going to get sizzling hot
# 你说我不愿用菜籽油
If you don't want to use canola oil
# 用花生油也行 没问题
Peanut oil works too, no problem
# 在家里做也方便
It's also convenient at home
# 准备啦 关键时刻
Be ready, this is it
# 上面喽
Noodles are ready
# 他这么着
Let's do it this way
# 油泼面走起
Come and have Biang Biang noodles!
# 嘿 有点意思啊
Hey, that's the feel
# 老饭骨人都会说话
People at Lao Fan Gu all know the ways to talk
# 陕西油泼面
Shanxi Biang Biang Noodles
# 你们也拿碗吃 不吃对不起
You all get bowls and join us, don't let us down
# 捞起捞起 捞福喽
get the blessing out of the bowl [blessing words]
# 挑福挑寿 捞福
get the blessing and longevity
# 这味调的正合适
The taste is just right
# 真筋道
Al dente!
# 加点葱香多了
It gets more aromatic with the scallion
# 油泼面走起
Come have Biang Biang noodles
# 油泼面走起 不对
Come have Biang Biang noodles... Oops
# 油泼面走起
Come have Biang Biang noodles!
# 踩着鸡脖子了
You cracked your voice
# 差一个羊皮袄子
All we miss is some Shanxi traditional sheepskin jacket